Guide to the Kenneth Tillson radio scripts
Oregon Historical Society Research Library
Kenneth Tillson radio scripts
1946-1949
Oregon Historical Society Research Library
Tillson, Kenneth, 1909-1985
Mss 2492
0.25 cubic feet 1 slim document case
Sixty-nine scripts, 1946-1949, for the radio program "Oregon Album," a Sunday afternoon show that aired on station KGW in Portland, Oregon, and dealt with events and personalities in Oregon history.
Collection is open for research.
Gift of Kenneth Tillson, April 1 and May 3, 1946.
Scripts are arranged by number, which is also chronological order by air date.
Kenneth H. Tillson (1909-1985) grew up in Portland, Oregon. He wrote radio scripts for stations KPOJ and KGW in Portland, and won a Peabody Award for an interview show called "On the Record." He moved to San Francisco, California, in 1951, where he continued his work in radio for stations KYA and KEAR, and later worked as a copywriter for advertising and public relations agencies. He retired in 1975.
Sources: Obituary in the San Francisco Examiner, April 2, 1985, Page E10; vital records on Ancestry.com.
Ninety-eight phonograph records of "Oregon Album" broadcasts are also held at the Oregon Historical Society Research Library.
The collection consists of 69 scripts, dating from 1946-1949, for "Oregon Album," a Sunday afternoon radio show that aired on Portland station KGW, and dealt with events and personalities in Oregon's history. The show was sponsored by Fields Chevrolet Company and featured dramatizations of historical events. The air date and time are printed on each script. Handwritten in the upper right corner of each script is the topic of the episode, as well as an episode or script number. Additional handwritten notes and marks appear on some of the scripts.
KGW (Radio station: Portland, Or.); Fields Chevrolet Company (Portland, Or.)
Oregon--History
Radio plays, American--Oregon--Portland; Radio broadcasting--Oregon--Portland; Radio advertising--Oregon--Portland; Advertising--Automobiles--Oregon--Portland
Oregon; Portland; Media and Communication
radio scripts
- Tonquin, No. 1, 1946 February 24 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Mary's River, No. 2, 1946 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Date printed on script is March 10, 1945; based on script number, the year is likely a typographical error.
- Fort George, No. 3, 1946 March 24 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Neahkahnie Mountain, No. 4, 1946 March 31 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- David McLoughlin, No. 5, 1946 April 7 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Indian Wars, No. 6, 1946 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Jason Lee Mission, No. 7, 1946 April 21 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Jim Logan, No. 8, 1946 April 28 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Dr. Owens-Adair, No. 9, 1946 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Sidney Smith, No. 10, 1946 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Lone Fox, No. 11, 1946 May 26 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Jesse Applegate, No. 12, 1946 June 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Timberline Lodge, No. 13, 1946 June 9 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Diary of Mrs. A. J. Butler, No. 14, 1946 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Joaquin Miller, No. 15, 1946 June 30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Oregon Historical Society, No. 16, 1946 July 7 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Crater Lake, No. 17, 1946 July 14 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Chief Joseph, No. 18, 1946 July 21 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- James Birnie, No. 19, 1946 August 18 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Thomas Hart Benton, No. 20, 1946 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Tonquin, No. 21, 1946 September 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Pendleton, Oregon, No. 22, 1946 September 8 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Wilson Price Hunt, No. 23, 1946 September 15 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Samuel Simpson, No. 24, 1946 September 22 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Barlow Road, No. 25, 1946 September 29 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Portland, No. 26, 1946 October 6? (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Date printed on script is October 3, 1946, but is probably a typographical error; the actual air date was likely October 6, 1946.
- Oswego, Oregon, No. 27, 1946 October 13 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Lewis & Clark, No. 28, 1946 October 20 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Oregon City, No. 29, 1946 October 27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- State Capital Fire, 1935, No. 30, 1946 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Council Crest, No. 31, 1946 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Portland Hotel, No. 32, 1946 November 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Samuel Hill, No. 33, 1946 November 24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Dallas, Oregon, No. 34, 1946 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Portland Art Museum, No. 35, 1946 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Chemaw Indian School, No. 36, 1946 December 15 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Name of school is misspelled as "Chemaw" on the script.
- Sanctuary of Our Sorrowful Mother, No. 37, 1946 December 22 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Review of Year of 1926, No. 38, 1946 December 29 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Vanport Center College, No. 39, 1947 January 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Mrs. Rogers -- Infantile Paralysis, No. 40, 1947 January 12 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Skiing, No. 41, 1947 January 19 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- California & Oregon Railway Co., No. 42, 1947 January 26 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Fort Yamhill, No. 43, 1947 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Columbia Basin Project, No. 44, 1947 February 9 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Frederic Homer Balch, No. 45, 1947 February 16 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Balch's first name is misspelled as "Frederich" on the script.
- Harvey Scott, No. 46, 1947 February 23 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Howard Maupin, No. 47, 1947 March 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Linfield College, No. 48, 1947 March 9 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Homer Davenport, No. 49, 1947 March 16 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Aurora Colony, No. 50, 1947 March 23 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Oregon Bulb Farms, No. 51, 1947 April 6 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Champoeg Wolf Meeting, No. 52, 1947 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Klamath Falls, No. 53, 1947 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Oregon's Myrtlewood, No. 54, 1947 May 11 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Forest Grove, Oregon, No. 55, 1947 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Walla Walla, Washington, No. 56, 1948 September 26 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Verne Bright, No. 57, 1948 October 3 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Port Orford, No. 58, 1948 October 24 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Tualatin Valley, No. 59, 1948 October 31 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Sauvie Island, No. 60, 1948 November 7 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Pioneer churches, No. 61, 1948 November 14 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Looking Glass Valley, No. 62, 1948 November 21 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Tongue Point, No. 63, 1948 November 28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Review of 1928, No. 64, 1948 December 26 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Sam Lancaster / Columbia River Highway, No. 65, 1949 January 16 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Elizabeth Dickson Smith / Geer diary, No. 66, 1949 January 23 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Oregon names, No. 67, 1949 January 30 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Canyon Road, No. 68, 1949 February 6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Eola, Oregon, No. 69, 1949 February 13 (Box 1, Folder 6)